# Abdulroqeeb Akinyele

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# **Profile**

An Intermediate software developer with professional experience in PHP/FLUTTER. I have an entrepreneurial attitude to the job, and bring a "can do" attitude to all aspects of my work. Ability to develop creative solutions for complex problems, while ensuring highest possible quality is achieved. I am highly experienced with integrating web services. I am also an excellent team worker with strong coaching and mentoring skill.

# **Employment History**

#### Sofware Developer, Macrotel Innovations Limited, Lagos

NOVEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Design and implementation of RESTFUL API for Mobile, Web, and USSD.
- Build cross-platform mobile apps with Flutter
- Supported USSD short code development.
- Documentation of customer journey for USSD flow.
- Support in programming a web-based Application supporting 15000 customers using CODEIGNITER.

#### Junior Developer and Buisness Analyst, Insurtech Ltd, Lagos

MARCH 2019 - NOVEMBER 2019

- Documentation of customer journey for USSD flow
- Meeting with managers of companies to discuss customer journey of their USSD and working the developers by explaining the customer journey and making sure they are in line with the flow
- Self-learning using online materials and trainings for personal development.
- Assisting technical authors with writing operational documentation
- Worked with the team in development of USSD (Unstructured Supplementary Service Data) for JAIZ BANK, ROYAL EXCHANGE.

# Graduate Research Assistant, Yabatech (Mechanical Engineering Department), Lagos

FEBRUARY 2017 - JULY 2017

- Leads efforts to develop and deploy standard work for each work area
- Meets regularly with supervisor to discuss research assignment
- Assisted with Academic research
- Assisted with the provision of research topics for undergraduates
- · Assisted with the make of buy analysis of the procurement planning

## Education

Mechanical Engineering, Federal University of Agriculture, Abeokuta, Lagos

SEPTEMBER 2011 - NOVEMBER 2016

# Courses

Responsive web ceritification, FreeCodeCamp

Google Africa Developer Training Program, Google Developers

#### **Details**

Lagos

Nigeria

07088338800

akinyeleroqeeb@gmail.com

## Links

LinkedIn

#### Skills

**SQL** 

PHP

MYSQL

HTML & CSS

**FLUTTER** 

DART

REACT

JAVASCRIPT

Codeigniter

jQuery

## British Project Management Professional Certification, Novelle

JUNE 2021 - JUNE 2021

## British Project Management Graduate Certification , Novelle

JUNE 2021 - JUNE 2021

# **PROJECTS**

## ZIPPYWORLD WEB APPLICATION

Backend/Frontend

## **Noor Takaful Mobile Application**

Mobile: Flutter

Backend: PHP, CODEIGNITER

## POLARIS BANK, UNION BANK, FIDELITY BANK, KEYSTONE

BACKEND: PHP, CODEIGNITER

# CREATION OF USSD API FOR SOVEREIGN TRUST INSURANCE(STI), ALLIANZ NIGERIA INSURANCE LIMITED, ARM PENSION

**BACKEND: PHP (CODEIGNITER)** 

# Extra-curricular activities

Branch President, MSSN, Ikeja, Lagos

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Web Developer, Hopewin, Lagos

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

# References

References available upon request